Finding Aid for Bernice G. Maynard photographs, ca. 1890-ca. 1910
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bernice G. Maynard photographs circa 1890-1910
Maynard, Bernice G.
0.4 linear feet
92631 Aa 2
Mrs. Frank Maynard, Ypsilanti, Michigan resident. Glass negatives and prints of photographs of unidentified family groups and other people, of Palmer's Drugstore in Ann Arbor, Michigan, of people with bicycles, of a military unit and band, and of the Homoeopathic Hospital at the University of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Bernice Maynard (donor no. 5413 ) and came to the library in 1973.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Bernice Maynard (Mrs. Frank Maynard) was a resident of Ypsilanti, Michigan. Further biographical information is lacking.
The collection consists of a single series of glass negatives relating to people, places, and events in Ann Arbor and at the University of Michigan. The glass negatives have been arranged into the following broad categories: Businesses and public places; Casual views of unidentified individuals - Ann Arbor area; Military scenes and marching bands; and Casual views of unidentified individuals. There is no information about the photographer of these images.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Bicycles and tricycles.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Children.; Families.; Interiors.; Military bands.; Palmer's Drugstore (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Pharmacies.; Soldiers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Homoeopathic Hospital.; Women.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Glass negatives
  - Businesses and public places (items 1-10)
    - Palmer's Drugstore, S. State Street, Ann Arbor, Michigan between 1896-1898. Sign for A.H. Holmes (Livery) in foreground., 1) (Box 1)
      also include copy negative and print
    - Woodward Avenue, Detroit. Street Scene showing C.H. Mills Furniture Store, Overman Wheel and Beals, Selkirk & Co. (trunks and bags)., 2) (Box 1)
    - Palmer's Drugstore, S. State Street (No. 46) 1896 or 1897. Window display with large bottle of "Pabst Malt Extract.", 3) (Box 1)
    - Palmer's Pharmacy, 46 S. State Street 1896-1897. Window display with large bottle of "Pabst Malt Extract", 4) (Box 1)
    - Resort Hotel or large Queen Anne home with wrap-around porch, with cupola and strollers, 5) (Box 1)
    - Man playing banjo, dressed in uniform; perhaps the interior of the Palmer Pharmacy, 6) (Box 1)
    - Man in apron pouring liquid into flask-perhaps interior of Palmer Pharmacy, 7) (Box 1)
    - Interior of steam plant (?) showing machinery labeled A. Harvey and Sons, Detroit, Michigan, 8) (Box 1)
    - Interior of steam plant (?) with four women and two men before tunnel, 9) (Box 1)
    - Man in derby hat sitting by a telephone and rolls of paper. A framed notice on the wall reads "Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti Railway...A.L. Noble", 10) (Box 1)
  - Casual views of unidentified individuals-Ann Arbor area (items 11-24)
    - Rear view of man walking towards a barbed wire fence, 11) (Box 1)
    - Two women standing on roof of shed behind a house Homeopathic Hospital, 12) (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan: Homeopathic Medical School (on North University Ave.), 13) (Box 1)
    - Sailboat and motor boat on lake, 14) (Box 1)
    - Man standing with bicycle next to large rock, 15) (Box 1)
    - Two women, one on a horse, the other standing next to her bicycle, 16) (Box 1)
    - Woman standing amidst many trees, hammock in background, 17) (Box 1)
    - Two women seated on front steps of house, 18) (Box 1)
    - Old woman seated indoors, large portrait (framed) on table to her right, 19) (Box 1)
    - Two women and man in horse and buggy in front of house, 20) (Box 1)
    - Six men posing casually in a field, 21) (Box 1)
    - Two men and two women standing indoors, one woman laughing, 22) (Box 1)
    - Woman reading to her daughter circa 1890s, 23) (Box 1)
    - Young men (team?) huddled in group, 24) (Box 1)
  - Military scenes and marching bands (items 25-34)
    - Marching Band, 25) (Box 1)
    - Soldiers standing with rifles; wearing tall helmets, 26) (Box 1)
    - Marching band in field, 27) (Box 1)
    - American flag and army tents, 28) (Box 1)
    - Soldiers standing around horses, 29) (Box 1)
    - Soldiers marching across field, U.S. flag in background, 30) (Box 1)
    - Soldiers standing with rifles, 31) (Box 1)
    - Soldiers standing around tents, some in line, 32) (Box 1)
    - Large group of soldiers lined up at attention, American flags present, 33) (Box 1)
    - General on horse parades before soldiers at attention, 34) (Box 1)
  - Casual views of unidentified individuals (items 35-57)
    - Men sitting around a dining room table, 35) (Box 1)
    - Two children (teens?) with bicycles, standing in front of buildings, 36) (Box 1)
    - Two young men peering out from a bedroom. An Ann Arbor calendar is on the wall, dated 1891, 37) (Box 1)
    - Interior: man jokingly asking for a lady's hand while friends peer out from behind a curtain, 38) (Box 1)
    - Two women strumming guitars, standing on wooden sidewalk., 39) (Box 1)
    - Family seated indoors, looking at an album, 40) (Box 1)
    - Interior-two men and two women sitting on a sofa, 41) (Box 1)
    - Interior-group of 10 people gathered around a potbellied stove, 42) (Box 1)
    - Interior-two young women and young child seated informally, talking to each other, 43) (Box 1)
    - Man in hat standing sideways to camera, looking upwards at a building behind him, 44) (Box 1)
    - Woman leaning against water pump, smiling at camera, 45) (Box 1)
    - Man in bowler hat posing with bicycle, 46) (Box 1)
    - Woman with back to camera in prow of rowboat, fishing gear sticking out from under her skirt, 47) (Box 1)
    - Man playing a flute sitting on front stoop. A large bottle labeled "Corkscrew Jamoca Ginger" is held between his knees, 48) (Box 1)
    - Girl wearing knickers posing with bicycle, 49) (Box 1)
    - Young girl and young man in backyard, smiling at each other, 50) (Box 1)
    - Interior-two men and two women sitting at table having tea, 51) (Box 1)
    - Lady and young woman with umbrella strolling through a yard, 52) (Box 1)
    - Interior-two men and a woman inside a parlor, 53) (Box 1)
    - Interior-man with saw and pliers pretending to be a dentist; friend in chair grimaces in mock agony, 54) (Box 1)
    - Interior-woman in underwear (long stockings and camisole), 55) (Box 1)
      (faded)
    - Two women behind barn pretending to be fighting; one holds scythe, 56) (Box 1)
    - "Khozzy Rhoost"-picnickers in front on tents circa 1890, 57) (Box 1)